J. Matthew Griffis (Matt)

Personal Statement

Game designer, interaction designer, and creative coder, with a well-rounded background emphasizing critical thinking and logic, collaboration, adaptability, intellectual strength, leadership, self-motivation, and imagination. I create playful interactive experiences about exploration and experimentation, creativity, reflection, reaction, and delight. I'm also a passionate musician and writer.

Education

Parsons The New School for Design--NYC, NY (May 2014)
Master of Fine Arts in Design and Technology

St. John's College--Santa Fe, NM (May 2008) Bachelor of Arts in Liberal Arts

Work Experience

Salk School of Science--NYC, NY (Feb. 2014 - May 2014)

Game Design and Programming Instructor

Taught game development to middle-school students, with a focus on programming in GameMaker Language (GML).

Parsons--NYC, NY (Aug. 2013 - May 2014) Graduate Teaching Assistant

Assisted with an undergraduate class teaching the technical skills of web design--HTML, CSS and JavaScript.

Parsons--NYC, NY (Oct. 2012 - May 2014) Graduate Research Assistant

Assisted the PETLab (Prototyping, Education and Technology Lab) with various projects to use games for public good.

Parsons--NYC, NY (March 2013 - August 2013) Bootcamp Teaching Fellow (Web)

Taught the introductory web development class to new Design and Technology graduate students during Bootcamp in August.

TreSensa, Inc.--NYC, NY (June 2013 - July 2013)

Game Design and Development Intern

Assisted with game design and development for mobile web, using an in-house engine based in JavaScript and HTML5.

Worked previously as <u>Customer Service Lead</u> and <u>Freelance Writer</u> (details upon request).

Contact Information

portfolio: jmatthewgriffis.com email: jmatthewgriffis@gmail.com

Fields of Specialty

Game design/development--theory and practice esp. digitally (through code)
Web design/development--hand-coded, responsive, interactive websites
Writing--creative and technical w/ critical thinking and analysis
Music--composition and performance

Computer Skills

Languages Platforms openFrameworks Unity C++ GameMaker C# GameSalad Processing Illustrator Java GitHub Windows JavaScript **HTML** OS X **CSS** Microsoft Office PHP Apple iWork Google Docs Arduino

Awards

University Merit--Parsons (2013-2014) Dean's Scholarship--Parsons (2012-2014)

Leadership

President, New School Game Club-Parsons (*March 2013 - Dec. 2013*)

Vice-President, dorkShop--Parsons (*Feb. 2013 - Oct. 2013*)

Representative, Student Council--Parsons (Sept. 2012 - Sept. 2013)